developermedia.com 2017-11-15

# Developer Media Privacy Policy - Developer MediaDeveloper Media | Tech Marketing Experts

Last updated: 2015-02-26

Developer Media is committed to protecting your privacy and to developing technology that gives you the most powerful and secure online experience.

This Privacy Policy explains data collection and use practices of Developer Media and Developer Media’s website developermedia.com (the “ **Site** “) (for the purposes of this Privacy Policy, Developer Media and the Site shall collectively be referred to as “ **We** ” or “ **Developer Media** “).

The “Site” refers to http://www.developermedia.com or anything that replaces, supplements, or supersedes the Site as the website of Developer Media.

By providing personal information to Developer Media, you are consenting to the information collection and use practices described in this Privacy Policy.

**THIS PRIVACY POLICY IS AN AGREEMENT. BY PROVIDING ANY PERSONAL INFORMATION TO THE SITE OR BY ACCESSING THE SITE, YOU ARE CONSENTING TO THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY, PLEASE DO NOT PROVIDE ANY PERSONAL INFORMATION TO DEVELOPER MEDIA.**

As part of our commitment to treat your personal information with respect, we operate in accordance with the following ten principles:

**Principle 1 – Accountability**  
**Principle 2 – Identifying Purposes**  
**Principle 3 – Consent**  
**Principle 4 – Limiting Collection**  
**Principle 5 – Limiting Use, Disclosure and Retention**  
**Principle 6 – Accuracy**  
**Principle 7 – Safeguarding Customer Information**  
**Principle 8 – Openness**  
**Principle 9 – Customer Access**  
**Principle 10 – Handling Customer Complaints and Suggestions**

## Principle 1 – Accountability

When you visit the Site and create a new membership account, you must provide us with your personal information, such as your name, email and physical address, zip/postal code, and telephone number.

We will maintain and protect the personal information under our control. We have designated an individual who is accountable for compliance with this Privacy Policy. If you have questions about our Privacy Policy or our use of your personal information, or if you need help changing your personal information or to opt-out, please contact us by sending an email to [webmaster@developermedia.com](mailto:Webmaster@developermedia.com) or contacting us at:

Developer Media  
503-250 Ferrand Drive  
Toronto, Ontario, Canada, M3C 3G8  
ph. +1 416-849-8900 x 100

## Principle 2 – Identifying Purposes

The purposes for which personal information is collected by us will be identified to you before or at the time the information is collected.

## Principle 3 – Consent

Except where required or permitted by law your informed consent is required for our collection, use or disclosure of your personal information.

## Principle 4 – Limiting Collection

The personal information collected by us shall be limited to those details necessary for the purposes identified to you. For example, if you are creating a new member account, we will collect certain information, such as your name, email and physical address, zip/postal code, and telephone number. Please note that Developer Media does not intentionally collect information from any individual under the age of 13 years and none of the material or advertising on the Site is intended to attract audiences under the age of 13.

If you would like to create a new member account, we will collect your name and email address. In addition, at your option, if you would like to increase your profile on the Site or with Developer Media generally, or if you would like to be considered by potential employers for employment (please see Principle 5 for a discussion on this point), you may also provide additional personal information you choose, including without limitation, a brief professional description, lists of interests and experience, where you live, the time zone in which you are in, your occupation, links to home pages, a picture of yourself and a message board signature.

Of course, any time you choose to post an editorial, or other message on the Site, that information is stored by Developer Media and is viewed, together with the biographical information you have provided, by all users of the Site.

**Please know that only your name and email is necessary to create a new member account, the provision of all other information is optional depending on what you are looking to do on the Site and with Developer Media.**

### Cookies

We use cookies, a piece of text stored on a user’s computer by their web browser, to store your viewing preferences on the Site and, at your choosing, to store your login information so that once you have logged in you do not need to repeat the login process. We also use a session cookie, meaning it expires soon after you leave the registration process and is not placed on your hard drive, to store your session information during your visit to the Site.

### Anonymous Information

In addition to personal information, certain anonymous information about your visit is automatically captured when you visit the Site. This information includes the name of the Internet service provider and the Internet Protocol (IP) address through which you access the Internet; the date and time you access the Site; the pages that you access while at the Site and the Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to the Site. None of this information is personally identifiable. This anonymous information is used to help improve the Site, analyze trends, and administer the Site.

## Principle 5 – Limiting Use, Disclosure and Retention

We will only use or disclose your personal information in accordance with the purposes for which it was originally collected unless you have otherwise consented, or when it is required or permitted by law.

### Use of your Personal Information

We use your personal information for the following purposes:

  * To register you for Site membership.
  * To customize your experience on the Site.
  * To send electronic email newsletters and information, if requested by you.
  * To fill in certain information for you such as your name and signature when posting to the Site.
  * To display your biography and other information submitted by you.

### Potential Professional Work Opportunities

Developer Media is often approached by, or engages with, corporations, business and other persons (“Employers”) who are looking to engage persons with various skill sets. For example, technical writing and creative/design services.  In some instances, Developer Media may try to accommodate such potential engagements by incorporating a “seeking professionals” section as part of the Site. In this instance, professional work engagements would be on the Site and Site users would contact the Employer directly.

Alternatively, Employers may choose to contact Developer Media directly and request that Developer Media provide to them personal information about those individuals who are interested in being considered for the professional work engagement and who have given their consent to Developer Media to provide their personal information to potential Employers.

With that in mind, if you choose, you can have your personal information made available by Developer Media to potential Employers. For those of you who choose to make your personal information available to potential employers, aside from providing additional resume type information to Developer Media, Developer Media will be storing the personal information (as Developer Media does with all information provided to it) for such uses and Developer Media will also sort such information in accordance with characteristics that potential Employers are looking for, and format such information in a manner easily reviewable by potential Employers.

**While Developer Media tries to ensure that potential Employers are legitimate, if you choose to make your personal information available to potential Employers, either through Developer Media or directly, Developer Media shall not bear any liability or responsibility   as a result of any action or inaction of the potential Employer, irrespective of whether such action or inaction is a result of providing your personal information to the potential Employer, the use such potential Employer makes of the personal information, or otherwise. **

### When Information May be Disclosed to Outside Parties:

Except as specifically provided for in this Privacy Policy, we do not disclose any personal information to third parties. Developer Media may disclose personal information in the following instances:

  1. To conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served to Developer Media, or the Site;
  2. To protect and defend the rights or property of Developer Media, including without limitation, investigating potentially fraudulent or questionable activities regarding your account(s) or the use of the Site;
  3. To act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Developer Media, the Site, or the public;
  4. To offer you related products and services that might benefit you, including information provided directly by third parties if you provide your consent to do so;
  5. In anticipation of and in the course of an actual or potential sale, reorganization, consolidation, merger or amalgamation of our business; and
  6. Otherwise as permitted or required by law.

The type of information we are legally required to disclose may relate to criminal investigations. In some instances such as a legal proceeding or court order, we may also be required to disclose certain information to authorities. Only the information specifically requested is disclosed and we take precautions to satisfy ourselves that the authorities that are making the request have legitimate grounds to do so.

In addition, Developer Media occasionally hires other companies to provide limited services on our behalf, including packaging, mailing and delivering prizes, answering customer questions about products and services, sending postal mail, and sending information about our products, special offers, and other new services. We will only provide those companies the personal information they need to deliver the service, and they are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose.

You may be offered the option to provide your information to certain third parties as part of an advertising promotion, special section, sponsored download, or other area on the Site. You will be made aware of the use of your information before you provide it, and the use thereof will be limited to the use to which you agreed.

### Email Addresses

Because email is the dominant form of communication between Developer Media and you, we wanted to address certain aspects of handling email addresses separately. Email addresses collected as part of the sign-up process are not made publicly available, except in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.  Most of the time, email addresses are simply used to confirm your identity and to communicate with you via email.

Occasionally, third parties want to send emails regarding offers to our members. Unless you authorize it we do not provide such third parties with your email address.  These third parties wishing to send offers to our members do so through us. They send us the offer and we email it to you on their behalf.

## Principle 6 – Accuracy

We shall make every reasonable effort to ensure your personal information is maintained in an accurate, complete and up-to-date form.

## Principle 7 – Safeguarding Personal Information

Developer Media takes all reasonable precautions to ensure the security, integrity and privacy of your personal information and honors your choices for its intended use. Personal information is stored in password-controlled servers with limited access and Developer Media utilizes technological safeguards such as security software and firewalls to deter any unauthorized access. While no security infrastructure is foolproof, we carefully protect your personal information from loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration or destruction.

### Our Employees and your Personal Information:

In the course of daily operations, access to personal information is restricted to authorized employees who have a legitimate business purpose and reason for accessing it. For example, when you call us, our designated employees will access your information to verify who you are and to assist you in fulfilling your requests.

As a condition of their employment, all employees of Developer Media are required to abide by the privacy standards we have established. Employees are informed about the importance of privacy and they understand that they are prohibited from disclosing any personal information to unauthorized individuals or parties.

## Principle 8 – Openness

If you would like a copy of our Privacy Policy we would be more than happy to provide one to you and it is always available on the Site. If you have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, please do not hesitate to contact us (see Principle 10 for our contact information).  .

## Principle 9 – Accessing and Amending Your Personal Information:

You have the right to access, verify and amend your personal information. You can review and edit your personal information at the Site by logging on to the Site with your logon email and password, and then clicking on the ‘My Settings’ link.

To help us keep your personal information up-to-date, we encourage you to amend inaccuracies and make corrections as often as necessary. Should you identify any incorrect or out-of-date information, notify us in writing and we will make the proper changes.

## Principle 10 – Handling Customer Complaints and Suggestions

If you have questions about our Privacy Policy or our use of your personal information, or if you need help changing or removing your personal information, please contact us by sending an email to [webmaster@developermedia.com](mailto:Webmaster@developermedia.com) or contacting us at:

Developer Media  
503-250 Ferrand Drive  
Toronto, Ontario, Canada, M3C 3G8  
ph. +1 416-849-8900 x 100

## GENERAL TERMS

### Third Party Websites

This Site may contain links to other websites. Please be aware that this Privacy Policy applies solely to the information collected on the Site. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any other websites. We encourage you to be aware when you are leaving this Site and read the privacy statements of each and every website that you visit before providing any personally identifiable information.

### Governing Law

This Privacy Policy, your use of the Site, and all related matters are governed solely by the laws of the Ontario, Canada and applicable federal laws of Canada, excluding any rules of private international law or the conflict of laws which would lead to the application of any other laws.

### Changes to This Privacy Policy

Developer Media reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy from time to time; however, all changes will be posted to this Privacy Policy at the time such changes are made. The date of the most recent revisions will appear on this page so please check back. Your continued use of the service constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Policy and any updates.
